

Ashwin Kumar M V

Principal full stack engineer with cloud experience



https://github.com/mvashwinkumar

in mvashwinkumar

Summary

Proficient full-stack engineer with over 9 years of experience in designing, developing, scaling, operating, and maintaining web applications. Experienced in front-end and back-end technologies, as well as DevOps practices. Seeking to leverage my technical skills and cross-domain exposure to make great products.

Skills

Azure

Architecting and deploying solutions



AKS, Cloud architecture, App service, AAD, Azure Devops, Billing, ACR, IAM, VNet, Event Hub, Storage Account

Full-stack JS

Javascript ecosystem

React, NodeJS, NextJS, NestJS, Typescript, Swagger, OIDC, Cesium, OpenSeaDragon, RabbitMQ, Playwright, Mongoose, TypeORM

Database

noSQL and SQL

MongoDB Atlas, Redis, MySQL, Postgres, Performance Optimization

Python ecosystem

Tools and Libraries

Flask, Pandas, NumPy, SciPy, OpenCV, Tensorflow, Kafka, OpenAI, Weaviate

Containers

Container build and orchestration

Docker, Kubernetes, Portainer, Openshift, AKS

DevOps

Code and Infrastructure Deployment

ARM, Helm, ArgoCD, Artifactory, Azure Pipelines, ACR

Collaboration tools

Source code, Communication, Planning, Ticketing

Azure Devops, Jira, Confluence, Gantt, DrawIO, Mermaid, Git, UML

Monitoring & Compliance

Tracing, Observability and Reporting

Azure Compliance Manager, Azure Policy, Sentry, Log Alerts, SonarQube, Istio, Jaeger

Certifications

Certified Kubernetes Application Developer

Cloud Native Computing Foundation

https://training.linuxfoundation.org/certification/verify/

Cred ID: CKAD-1900-002064-0100

Cert. Agile Fundamentals

SoftEd Singapore

Agile certification on fundamentals

Awards

P2 Award March 2024

TÜV SÜD Asia Pacific Pte Ltd

P2 Award from CEO of Digital Service Singapore for taking up the initiative to review the high cloud subscription costs, identifying and executing improvement plans to achieve a 42% reduction in Lift Manager operating costs.

December 2019

Experience

TÜV SÜD Asia Pacific Pte Ltd

July 2021 - Present

Principal Engineer, Full-stack

https://www.tuvsud.com/en-sg

Singapore

- Commercialize smart inspection solution for lifts with data analysts to monitor lift health, detect anomalies and alert for predictive maintenance in near real-time. Setup and maintain operations for more than 200 lifts with almost zero downtime on azure kubernetes services, along with event driven processing with Event hubs
- Developed smart inspection solution for facade inspection of buildings and perform period inspection digitally through web application. This application is powered by 3d models, AI detection of facade defects independently developed and integrated into the platform workflow
- Supporting devops, devlopment, code review, quality checks, hosting vendor evaluation and operations monitoring for bill & melinda gates foundation funded projects in colloboration with Sanitation Services dept
- Automated tasks with internal tools to streamline development experience across project teams, standardize CI/CD processes, migrate tooling and common infrastructure to cloud when needed, guide junior developers with software development practices
- Work along with other principal engineers to improve architecture, focus on scalability and uptime. Regularly focus to improve on tools selection

AXA Insurance Pte Ltd June 2018 - Jul 2021

Assistant Manager, Digital Operations

Singapore

- https://www.insurance.hsbc.com.sg/
- Led development team on New Retail Platform (Renewals and Endorsement) by leveraging and extending the platform capabilities
- Enhanced platform from synchronous architecture to scalable, resilient asynchronous message-driven architecture with queues
- Optimized the performance of core pricing compiler, introduced a custom testing framework, and thus reduced turn around time for preparation of pricer from several weeks to a couple of days
- Introduced dynamic templating into product configuration, enabling centralized management of all products with unified workflow, contributed to the development of internal product configuration interface libraries for microservices, improved integration testing using production configuration workflow
- Integrated the platform with external commercial partners to sell insurance directly through partner websites via API and iframes
- Worked with multiple stakeholders in scrum format, delivering incremental changes to the product
- Contributed to shared resources and promoted knowledge sharing across teams by organizing DevTalks

Eatigo Singapore Pte Ltd

Apr 2017 - Jun 2018

Front-end Engineer

Singapore

- https://eatigo.com/sg/singapore/en
- Developed Admin Portal for back-office operations, reviewed development of Consumer website with third party and performed optimizations; hosted on AWS

Fuji Xerox Asia Pacific Pte Ltd

Dec 2014 - Apr 2017

Senior software engineer

Singapore

- https://www.fujifilm.com/fbsg/en
- Implemented core features in the native Address book for TOKIWA
- Provided SDK integration and localization for existing devices
- Automated deployment by building in-house tools; enhanced workflow
- Optimized "question answering" application, performing text extraction, normalization, using machine learning models and profiler

Land Transport Authority

Apr 2014 - Sep 2014

Software engineer (intern)

Singapore

- https://www.lta.gov.sg/content/ltagov/en.html
- Independently developed Single Page Application in front-end for Passenger Service Machine and Station Computer Map, this is currently in use at all MRT stations throughout Singapore

Education

National University of Singapore

2014

IT Systems Analysis

Full-time

4.76/5.00

https://www.iss.nus.edu.sg/graduate-programmes/programme/detail/graduate-diploma-in-systems-analysis

Second best in class and won ISS Booker Prize.

Studied hands-on IT systems analysis and software development lifecycle methodology with Agile primer.

National Institute of Technology, Rourkela

2011 Full-time

Electrical Engineering (BTech)

8.47

https://www.nitrkl.ac.in/EE

Graduated with honors class.